Wenda Qiu

🖂 qiuwenda@sjtu.edu.cn 💆 akigeor.github.io Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Objective

I am an undergraduate student from Shanghai Jiao Tong University (SJTU) ACM Honors Class, Zhiyuan College (an honors college) and major in computer science. I have a great passion on my major and enjoy conducting scientific research. I am determined to join the academia in the future.

Education

2015.9–2019.6 **Bachelor of Engineering**, Computer Science and Technology.

(Expected) Shanghai Jiao Tong University ACM Honors Class, Zhiyuan College, GPA: 3.5/4.0

Experience

2018.7-2018.12

University of Research Assistant guided by Prof. Jiawei Han.

Illinois at Urbana- I worked as a visiting research assistant at University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign un-Champaign, der the instruction of Prof. Jiawei Han since July 2018. My research topic is about text data mining.

- Synonym-Aware Entity Set Expansion
 - Synonym detection and semantic entity set expansion are both fundamental tasks for many applications.
 - Proposed a novel framework to combine entity set expansion with synonym set discovery and to enable two tasks to mutually enhance each other.
 - Formulated the entity set expansion as a positive-unlabeled learning task and designed an effectively ensemble-based linear classifier to solve this task efficiently.
 - Conducted extensive experiments on 10 manually selected semantic classes and demonstrated the proposed framework could improve the state-of-the-art methods by 48% relatively in terms of MAP@100.

Tong University, 2017.7-2018.6

Shanghai Jiao Research Assistant guided by Prof. Hongtao Lu.

I worked as a research assistant at Shanghai Jiao Tong University under the supervision of Prof. Hongtao Lu. My research topic is image style transfer using image-to-image networks which belongs to computer vision field.

Image Style Transfer

Image style transfer is an impressive application of generative models.

 Conducted extensive literature survey and implemented image-to-image networks including VAE, GAN and W-GAN in Pytorch.

Shanghai Jiao Shanghai Jiao Tong University ACM-ICPC Team Member.

2015.6-2017.5

Tong University, I joined SJTU ACM-ICPC (a world-wide team-based computer problem solving competition) group since summer of 2015.

World Finals 2017

Represented Shanghai Jiao Tong University in the ACM-ICPC World Finals 2017. Our strong teamwork ensured us a deserved champion in Asia Tsukuba regional 2016 and we advanced to World Finals 2017.

Shanghai Jiao Shanghai Jiao Tong University ACM-ICPC Team Leader.

2017.6-2018.4

Tong University, I served as the leader for representative team of our university.

• World Finals 2018

Stood out in regional contests and won the qualification to participate in ACM-ICPC World Finals 2018. As the most senior student in the team, I brought all my experiences into play and our team achieved a silver medal in the World Finals 2018.

Awards

- 2018.4 ACM-ICPC World Finals 2018, 8th Place, Silver Medal.
- 2017.5 ACM-ICPC World Finals 2017. 13th Place.
- 2017.11 The 2017 ACM-ICPC Asia Beijing Regional Contest, 2nd Place, Gold Medal.
- 2016.10 The 2016 ACM-ICPC Asia Tsukuba Regional Contest, 1st Place, Gold Medal. ACM-ICPC stands for ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest. You may find a full list of my ICPC awards at icpc.baylor.edu/ICPCID/TSIL76L1GG4Y.
- 2016, 2017 **Zhiyuan Honorary Scholarship**, SJTU top 5%.

Zhiyuan College offers an honors program and scholarship to selected students among SJTU Top 5% undergraduate students.

2014.7 The 2014 National Olympiad in Informatics of China, Silver Medal.

Manuscripts

2018.12 Wenda Qiu*, Jiaming Shen*, Jingbo Shang, Michelle Vanni, Brian Sadler, and Jiawei Han. SynSetExpan: Synonym-Aware Entity Set Expansion, In preparation for KDD 2019. *Equal Contribution

Projects

Advanced Data Led a team of three people and implemented several advanced data structures including:

- Y-Fast-Trie, a structure storing integers from a bounded domain. Structure
 - Dominator Tree, a structure finding dominators in control flow graphs.
 - \circ Rank-pairing-Heap, a priority queue works $O(\log n)$ amortized time in delete-min operation and O(1) in others.
- MIPS CPU Implemented a CPU with five-stage MIPS pipeline using Verilog programming language.

Benchmark for Proposed an effective evaluation method involving focus map analysis to measure how a Visual Question visual question answering (VQA) system's reasoning capability rather than remembering the Answering bias to get correct answers.

Attack on This is a group project for a research course given by Prof. John Hopcroft.

Networks

Image-to-image Conducted experiments studying how adversarial examples (intentional noise added to input) mislead image-to-image network's output.

Next Frame Studied and applied β -VAE and optical flow in frame synthesizing task to get a more Synthesizing precise prediction and a disentangled latent vector where each dimension controls a part's movement.

Skills

Languages

Programming C++, Python, Java, Pascal

Deep Learning Pytorch, Tensorflow

Platforms

Computer Skills Git, Vim, LATEX, Microsoft Office

English TOEFL iBT 104/120